Noel Wilson

Flat 5, 67 gloucester Street, Victoria, London SW1V 4DZ 07756958746 · Mobile · jwnwilson@gmail.com

Website: http://www.noel-wilson.co.uk/

Linked in: http://www.linkedin.com/pub/noel-wilson/25/942/a1

Single · British Age – 27

Full Stack Developer

PROFILE

An experienced Python, C++ and Java programmer, with a strong VFX background, has been using python to create applications, software, tools and scripts for years in a professional environment. Being a keen problem solver, has the ability to rapidly adapt, learn and create effective solutions in any environment. Addicted to learning and wants to master his craft, fiercely determined and able to take on difficult tasks, self-educate any skills and act on criticism given, always learning new skills and reading to grow and develop as a programmer.

Spends free time working on personal projects such as Python / Django web servers, C++ and Java Applications. Has a strong background in object orientated programming with the use of software design patterns, practices, source control management and automated testing which makes integrating into a new environment easy and improves the quality of code produced. Examples of past works are available on the website above.

A friendly and easy going individual with strong communication skills that compliment an ability to work well in a team, having worked in large and small groups, has lead projects and followed other leads. Can manage own time and small teams, prioritise tasks, effectively handle problems and find solutions quickly and efficiently. Enjoys helping team mates, communicates well with the group also able to communicate with clients and contacts in other companies in a professional and productive manner.

EDUCATION

BSc Animation and Visual Effects programming (2:1) -University of Teesside 2006 - 2009 MA Digital Animation, Sound and Visual Media-University of Teesside 2009- 2010

WORK EXPERIENCE

Astreya Partners Inc @ Google

Software Developer

January 2015 - Present

- Built tools used by hundreds of employees around the world to increase productivity.
- Managed release cycles and deployment / roll out of tools.
- Trusted with sensitive data and reliability of tools effecting SLAs
- Worked with one of the largest and most renown tech companies in the world, with access to learning their tools and practices.

Prime Focus World

Software Developer

October 2013 - January 2015

- Had to build and maintain multiple core tools and applications for hundreds of people in a large global company.
- Implemented continuous integration with Jenkins for a team able to automated complicated tests.
- Implemented automated error tracking / handling able to notify developers of problems as soon as they happen.

Had To work with teams over the world.

IDXtra

Software Developer / Project manager

October 2012 – October 2013

- Had to refactor and introduce good programming practices such as DRY, proper source code control, modulation and readability.
- Had to Setup and manage programming projects planning release cycles, versioning and managing bugs / support.
- Had to improve / add new features while incrementally improving existing code using continuous integration with Jenkins.
- Had to manage self and other programmers on projects.
- Had to train interns.

Framestore

Rigger / Technical director

February 2011 – August 2012

- Has worked on various films creating assets, software and tools for others working mainly with Python and MEL.
- Had To QA all assets, software and tools making sure they matched a strict film pipeline and set of requirements by users, using scripts and test scenarios.
- Has edited and added to large custom libraries.

Back to Front Animation Junior Technical Director

July 2010 - February 2011

- Had to create and maintain assets using Python and MEL
- Created tools and user interfaces with scripts.
- Had to find effective solutions quickly and implement them with tight deadlines.
- Had to be constantly learning new techniques and tools to match demanding tasks every day.

ACTIVITIES

Gymnastics Coaching *November 2012 – Present:*

- Had to organise and supervise multiple groups of children aged 5-16 planning long term goals and tailoring lessons to individual needs.
- Has coached large groups of adults able to effectively instruct, teach, manage and ensure safety of all students.

SKILLS

•	Python	Java
•	Javascript	C++
•	Django	\mathbf{SQL}
•	QT Libraries	NoSQL

• Html and CSS skills Google App Engine expertise

• Apache NGINX

• Management Skills Teaching skills

INTERESTS

- Personal Programming projects
- Coaching (Gymnastics)
- Sports (Kickboxing, Gymnastics)
- Socialising & networking

REFERENCES

Available on request.